PEERAPAT ASOKTUMMARUNGSRI

Tel: +66894446110 Skype: nuboat

Email: nuboat@gmail.com

39/207 I-HOUSE Laguna Garden RCA, Bangkapi, Huaykwang, Bangkok 10310

Profile

I have been working as a software engineer with more than 13 years of experiences in Unix/Linux, Oracle Database, C/C++, Python, Java Platform and Web Technology. My clients are included, but not limited to, retails and banking industry. Presently, I'm a Contributor of Oracle User Group in Thailand (http://oracle.in.th) and Founder of Thailand Java User Group (http://thjug.com). I'm also a speaker at Thailand Practical Software Engineer (http://www.tpseconf.org) on software engineering topic, A guest speaker at Taipei Big Data Conference 2015 (http://bigdataconf.ithome.com.tw), A staff of Agile Community in Thailand. Moreover, I am also provide consulting services on Java platform to various company. As for my full-time employment, I am currently a member of the Platform Team at Agoda. I am responsible for develop and maintenance Hotel Search API with Scala -Play Framework, and Cassandra, Analytic hotel data with Hadoop and HIVE on CDH platform. Finally design and implement customer marketing platform base on Big Data technology such as Kafka and Spark

Education

King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang Bachelor, Computer Engineer, 2000 - 2004

Skills

Unix/Linux, Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS, Glassfish,
JBoss, Virtual Box, Vagrant, Docker, VM Ware, Couchbase,
Cassandra, MongoDB, OrientDB,

SQL-92, Java, Python, C, Scala, Primefaces, SAML, Spring, Selenium, HTML5, EJB, JPA, JAX-RS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Django, D3.JS, Playframework, Akka, Guice

Cloudera, Hadoop, HIVE, ZooKeeper, Kafka, Oozie, MapReduce, HUE, Spark

IntelliJ, Netbeans, Maven, SBT, Gradle, Git, Android Studio

Conferences

Thailand Practical Software Engineer 2013 - Code Quality with Sonar

Thailand Practical Software Engineer 2015 - Scaleable Database with Cassandra

Taipei Big Data Conference 2015 - Data Pipeline with Kafka and Akka

Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Agoda, Bangkok, Thailand — October, 2014 - present

- 1. Implement Hotel Search API with Scala Play Framework, Akka, Kafka, Couchbase and Cassandra. Implement pre-calculation engine with Akka and Kafka to pre calculate hotel price on specific date and save into Cassandra. Analyze a lots of statistic data with Hadoop(such as Ranking). Deploy and Operate production environment with Puppet Script.
- 2. Implement a new Customer Marketing Platform with Spark(For Realtime process) and Scala Play Framework(For Scheduler and Dashboard Monitoring). Integrate to big marketing platform such as ExactTarget and SendGrid.

Software Engineer II, Fair Isaac, Bangkok, Thailand Mar 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 8 months)

FICO Customer Dialogue Manager (CDM), CDM is multichannel marketing platforms which implements based on JavaEE and EJB, In project I has take responsibility on first part of project, design architecture, POC, implements security part of project based on Spring-Security and SAML, implements RESTful with JAX-RS and some part of UI with JSF and Primefaces.

Software Engineer, Chalkboard Pte. Ltd., Singapore Mar 2011 - Jan 2012 (1 year)

Chalkboard is a mobile and web advertising platform that makes it easy for business owners to communicate your daily specials, promotions and product launches to consumers around your establishment.

- I developed 3 majors and design cloud system at Chalkboard
- 1. Chalkboard API this is the RESTful web services.

We use Python Django and mod_wsgi for web & location services API.

2. Data Analytic on MongoDB

Created MapReduce data script for calculate analytic data.

3. Chalkboard Android Widget

Chalkboard is partner with HTC. We build Chalkboard Widget for preload it to HTC phone.

4. Cloud Infrastructure, Setup and Deploy current system on Amazon Web Services for high performance and high reliability on low price.

System Analyst & Architecture, Infinite Computing Systems, Bangkok, Thailand Jul, 2009 - Mar, 2011 (1 years 9 months)

Lead internal CMB team to develop software bases on Java EE and working with foreigner outsource.

CMB use Murex & Oracle, My team take responsibility to implement web front end to help client manage the system and integration data between Murex and other bank system (such as EDW, OGL, ..).

System Analysis, COD, Bangkok, Thailand Feb, 2008 - Jun, 2009 (1 year 6 month)

Develop Processing Banking System(PBS) for large bank in Thailand with Python + Twisted and Oracle Database to provide XML-RPC services, this project is core system which will provide services for another bank system such as e-cheque.

Developer, RingZero Network, Bangkok, Thailand Feb, 2006 - Jan, 2008 (2 years)

1. Store Accounting System of 7-11

Web application for handle branch accounting based on JavaEE and Oracle Database

2. Smartcard & Payment System

Reduced Time & Increased Stability for purchase with Smart purse

Developer, GE Money Thailand, Bangkok, Thailand Feb, 2005 - Jan, 2006 (1 year)

Develop & Support CRM Operational team in GE Money Thailand

- 1. Implement ETL with PL/SQL
- 2. Production support to Telesales & Home Mortgage sales
- 3. Implemented Home Mortgage salesforce based on Servlet & Oracle. This the web application and workflow.

 Implement mobile version on window mobile for sale team, web application workflow for HQ and MIS report for director & head of sale team.

Developer, iT One, Bangkok, Thailand Sep, 2004 - Jan, 2005 (5 month)

I have one of large team in itOne. We have implemented web application workflow for Siam Yamato Steel with .NET technology, This project has responsibility for manage manufacturing steel on SCG plant. and I have created report for CPAC with PL/SQL when I worked at itOne

Community

Contributor, <u>OUGTH</u>, Bangkok, Thailand — Jan, 2006 - present

Contributor of Oracle User Group in Thai.

Founder, THJUG, Bangkok, Thailand - Jan, 2013 - present

Founder of Thailand Java User Group. Organize event regarding to Java Technology. Contribute Java knowledge. URL: http://www.thjug.com

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/groups/thjug

Staff, AGILE66, Bangkok, Thailand - Jan, 2015 - present Staff of Agile66, The First Agile Community in Thailand Facebook: http://facebook.com/groups/agile66

Interests

Novel, Anime, Manga, Games, Swimming, Cat, Traveling, Photography, Coffee, Scuba, Food, Movie, Shopping

References

references upon you request.